One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
A world... Yes!
Bir dünya... Evet!
A world for you who seek freedom stretches out right before your eyes.
Senin gibi özgürlüğü arayan biri için koca bir dünya tam gözlerinin önünde.
If you feel guided by endless dreams,
Sonu olmayan rüyaların peşinden gitmek istiyorsan,
surpass them, flying the flag of your beliefs!
inandıklarının bayrağını taşıyarak onların ötesine geç!
I've just now begun to search, over the splashing waves
Engin dalgaların üzerinde, sonsuz dünyayı arayışım...
For the everlasting world
henüz yeni başladı.
With this overflowing passion in my chest,
İçime sığmayan tutkuyla,
I will go anywhere
kimselerin görmediği ışığın peşinden...
Seeking the light yet unseen
nereye olursa giderim.
When the summer sun stirs my heart's sails
Yaz güneşi, kalbimin yelkenlerini hareketlendiriyor...
That's the signal to open the door to a new world
İşte yeni bir dünyaya açılan kapının işareti bu…
Swaying on the waves, reaching beyond despair
Dalgalar üstünde sallanıp umutsuzluğu aşarak…
Aiming for the other side of the horizon
ufkun öteki tarafını hedef alıyorum.
I've just now begun to search, over the splashing waves
Engin dalgaların üzerinde, sonsuz dünyayı arayışım...
For the everlasting world
henüz yeni başladı.
With this overflowing passion in my chest
İçime sığmayan tutkuyla,
I will go anywhere
kimselerin görmediği ışığın peşinden...
Seeking the light yet unseen
nereye olursa giderim.
You should hurry before the boat goes deeper into the Lost Woods!
Botunuz, Kayıp Orman'ın derinliklerinde kaybolmadan acele etmelisiniz!
The Village Hidden in the Clouds
Saklı Bulut Köyü
Hey!
Hey!
We gotta go after the boat before it gets away!
Bir an önce botun peşinden gitmeliyiz!
It'll be a disaster if we lose it in this forest!
Kaybedersek felaket olur!
Wait, Usopp!
Bekle, Usopp!
The same can be said if we get separated!
Ayrılırsak da felaket olacak!
Luffy! What about you?!
Luffy! Sen ne diyorsun?!
You guys stop the boat!
Siz botu durdurun!
I'll take care of the ball guy!
Toparlağı bana bırakın!
In your dreams!
Rüyanda görürsün!
I'm filled with bliss and pride!
İhtişam ve neşe doluyumdur!
I guess we do need someone to stop that Daruma.
Bu tombik ucubeyi birimizin durdurması gerekiyor!
Don't do anything reckless!
Dikkatsiz davranma!
He's got some weird powers!
Garip güçleri var!
We'll return once we stop the boat!
Botu durdurup döneceğiz!
Got it!
Tamamdır!
Stay right there, ball!
Bir yere kıpırdama, toparlak!
He grabs a branch...
Dalı tutacak...
Gum-Gum...
Lastik-Lastik...
It's the same as before.
Aynı az önceki gibi.
...Pistol!
...Tabanca!
To my left!
Soluma doğru!
Don't be in such a rush!
O kadar acele etme!
Stay for a while!
Biraz bekle!
Now then, where did the other two go?
Şimdi, diğer ikisi nereye gitti?
I won't let a single one escape!
Hiçbirinin kaçmasına izin vermeyeceğim!
There you are!
İşte oradasın!
Hey! Do you see it, Usopp?!
Hey! Görüyor musun, Usopp?!
Found it!
Gördüm!
Give me directions!
Yerini tarif et!
Straight ahead!
Düz devam et!
Climb up the tree after the next!
Bir sonraki ağaca tırman!
You can jump onto it from the branches!
Dallardan ona atlayabilirsin!
Got it!
Anladım!
Yikes! It's him!
Sıçtık! Bu o!
What's he up to?!
Ne yapacak?!
Go!
Git bakalım!
Look out, Sanji!
Dikkat et, Sanji!
There's a ball headed your way!
Sana doğru gelen bir top var!
What?! What's Luffy doing?!
Ne?! Luffy ne yapıyor?!
Surprise Billiard!
Bilardo Sürprizi!
Usopp!
Usopp!
He was aiming for me!
Hedef benmişim!
It's gonna explode!
Patlayacağım!
"Pop"?!
Çiçek mi?!
Just a dud, huh?
Yanlış top, ha?
Idiot!
Aptal!
You bastard!
Seni şerefsiz!
Gum-Gum...
Lastik-Lastik...
Gatling!
Mitralyöz!
Stop it, Luffy!
Dur, Luffy!
Don't hit those balls blindly!
Toplara öyle rastgele vurma!
What the...?! What's going on?!
Ne...?! Ne oluyor?!
It's over!
İşimiz bitti!
It's too late!
Artık çok geç!
Look out!
Dikkat edin!
They're coming from all directions!
Her yönden geliyorlar!
You people are fun!
Siz de amma eğlenceli çıktınız!
Spears!
Mızraklar!
Crab!
Yengeç!
Four at once!
Dört tane birden!
For real?
Cidden mi?
More duds?
Bunlarda mı yanlış çıktı?
Hot!
Sıcak!
Hot, hot, hot, hot, hot!
Sıcak, sıcak, sıcak, sıcak, sıcak!
Water!
Su!
Water, water, water!
Su, su, su!
Hot! Hot, hot, hot!
Off! Sıcak, sıcak, sıcak!
Hot, hot, hot, hot, hot!
Yandım! Yandım, yandım, yandım!
The river!
Nehir!
That hurts!
Çok acıdı!
I fell through!
Düşüyorum!
Luffy!
Luffy!
Don't land in the river below!
Sakın nehre düşme!
There might not be a bottom!
Dibi olmayabilir!
What?
Ne?
That was close!
Ucuz atlattım!
Are you a moron?!
Salak mısın lan sen?!
Usopp Hammer!
Usopp Çekici!
Rubber Band!
Lastik Bant!
Yahoo!
Yehuu!
Oh! I totally forgot about that!
Ah! Onu tamamen unutmuştum!
Now's my chance to try it out!
Şimdi denemenin tam zamanı!
Did you come up with something, Usopp?!
Bir planın mı var, Usopp?!
I sure did!
Tabii ki var!
I'm known as the greatest pirate inventor after all!
Sonuçta gelmiş geçmiş en iyi mucit korsan benim!
I'll show you my latest weapon!
Size nihai silahımı göstereceğim!
Usopp...
Usopp...
Aah-eeh-aaaaaah!
Aaa-aa-aaaaaa!
What in the world?
Bu da neydi?
Just wait and see!
Bekle ve gör!
There it is!
İşte orada!
On the river straight ahead!
Tam ileride nehirde!
I can make it!
Yapabilirim!
Set Up!
Yerleş!
What's he trying to do?
Ne yapıyor bu?
Alright!
Pekâlâ!
Now it's just a straight line to the Little Crow!
Şimdi Küçük Karga tam karşımda!
If it travels any further, we won't be able to reach it!
Biraz daha ilerlerse onu kaybedeceğiz!
I won't get another chance like this!
Bu fırsatı iyi değerlendirmeliyim!
Wow!
Vaay!
Not too shabby!
Hiç fena değil!
Watch out for the balls!
Toplara dikkat et!
I'm not gonna screw this one up!
Bu fırsatı kaçırmayacağım!
You can call me the king of the jungle!
Bana ormanın kralı diyebilirsiniz!
Here I go!
İşte gidiyorum!
Usopp...
Usopp...
Aah-eeh-ah-eeh-aaaaaah -eeh-ah-eeh-aaaaah!
Aaa-aa-aa-aa-aaaaaa!
What's wrong?! Just stick the landing!
Ne yapıyorsun?! Bota atlasana!
Yeah...
Evet...
about that...
aslında...
I forgot...
düşününce...
that the rope is attached to the belt, so I can't get loose!
halatın kemera bağlı olduğunu unuttum, o yüzden atlayamıyorum!
Dammit! Dammit! Dammit!
Kahretsin! Kahretsin! Kahretsin!
Just... a bit... farther...
Biraz... daha... ileri...
Yahoo!
Yehuu!
Hey, Usopp!
Hey, Usopp!
You seem to be having fun too!
Sen de eğleniyor gibisin!
I need a word with you two.
Size söyleyecek birkaç şeyim var.
Got it?
Anladınız mı?
If you follow my lead, I'll forget what just happened.
Bundan sonra dediklerimi dinlerseniz yaptıklarınızı unuturum.
Yes. I'm sorry.
Evet. Özür dilerim!
I'm very sorry.
Çok özür dilerim.
Forget about the boat for now.
Botu şimdilik unutun.
All three of us need to attack him at once.
Ona üçümüz aynı anda saldırmalıyız.
I don't care if he is a priest.
Rahip olması umurumda değil.
Attacking him as a group ought to put him down for good!
Eğer beraber saldırırsak onu bir şekilde yenebiliriz!
Beat me?!
Beni yenmek mi?!
Where'd he go?!
Nereye gitti?!
Impact!
Darbe!
Sanji!
Sanji!
To live is to suffer.
Yaşamak acı çekmekten ibarettir...
Now then...
Biri gitti...
Only two left.
Kaldı iki.
A-All right!
P-Pekâlâ!
Good thing this was here!
İyi ki bu bende!
Got it?
Anladınız mı?
I'll hold on to this whistle!
Düdük bende duracak!
Any objections?!
İtirazı olan var mı?!
– Yes!
– Evet!
Yes! Yes!
Evet! Evet!
How can you all say that?!
Ne demek itirazımız var?!
I'm the frailest girl here!
Burada en çok yardıma ihtiyacı olan benim!
It's only natural that I hold onto this whistle!
Düdüğün bende durması gerekiyor!
I wanna blow it!
Çalmak istiyorum!
You just wanna test it out, Luffy! Forget it!
Sen sadece test etmek istiyorsun, Luffy! Çıkar aklından bunu!
I wanna call the old man right now!
İhtiyarı çağırmak istiyorum!
Let me hold on to it!
Bırakın bende kalsın!
I'm the weakest!
En güçsüz olan benim!
You wish! I'm the weakest one of all!
Hadi oradan! En güçsüzünüz benim!
What?! Quit screwing around!
Ne?! Saçmalamayın!
I'm clearly the weakest here.
Apaçık belli, en güçsüz benim!
No, I am! I'm the weakest!
Hayır, benim! Benim en güçsüz!
Don't underestimate my hopelessness!
Benim zavallılığımı hafife almayın!
I wanna blow the whistle!
Düdüğü ben çalmak istiyorum!
What a strange argument...
Ne kadar ilginç bir tartışma...
Let's do this, then!
Tamam o zaman!
Center of the ship!
Geminin tam ortasında...
I'll hang it on the main mast,
ana direğin olduğu yere asıyoruz.
so if anyone's in trouble, they can grab and blow the whistle!
Başı derde giren, alıp çalabilir!
Now it's fair!
Şimdi adil oldu!
Alright.
Pekâlâ.
Got it.
Anladım.
Oh, also...
Ah, bir de...
none of you have permission to blow it!
size düdüğü çalmak yasak!
But I wanna call the old man...
Ama ihtiyarı çağırmak istiyorum...
Blow it, and I'll kick your ass off this planet!
Hele bir çalın, sizi yok ederim!
– Yes, ma'am. We'll be careful. – Yes ma'am. We'll be careful.
– Anlaşıldı. Çalmayız.
Now if anything happens, the Sky Knight will come save me!
Bir şey olursa, Gökyüzü Şövalyesi gelip beni kurtaracak!
But the whistle is a last resort!
Ama düdüğü başka çarem kalmadığında çalmalıyım!
Alright!
Pekâlâ!
I'll do my very best to watch over the ship!
Gemiyi korumak için elimden geleni yapacağım!
What's that?
O ne öyle?
Huh?
Ha?
You're the only sacrifice I get to kill?
Bir tek sen mi kurban edileceksin?
This year's pumpkins grew exceptionally well.
Bu yıl kabaklar olağanüstü iyi yetişti.
Oh...
Evet...
I cannot find the words to express my gratitude.
Minnetarlığımı ifade edecek kelimeler bulamıyorum.
I'm sorry.
Özür dilerim.
You ended up taking me in as well.
Beni de yanınıza almak zorunda kaldınız.
If they decide that your daughter let those Straw Hat fellows escape,
Kızının Hasır Şapkalar'ın kaçmasına yardım ettiği hükmüne varırlarsa,
you'll be considered an accomplice.
seni de suç ortağı sayarlar.
Your life is in danger.
Hayatın tehlikede olabilir.
This time is on the house...
Bu seferlik benden olsun...
Enel's mantra does not reach this far.
Enel'in mantrası buraya erişemiyor.
How are things on Angel Island?
Melek Adası'nda durumlar nasıl?
Come again?
Pardon?
I'm referring to the crops.
Mahsülleri diyorum.
Are they doing better this year?
Bu yıl daha iyi mi?
Yes, they seem to be coming along quite well.
Evet, gayet iyi diye duydum.
Is that so?
Öyle mi?
I'm glad to hear it.
Sevindim.
This is juice made from the pumpkins I grew in my field.
Bu benim yetiştirdiğim kabaklardan.
It's delicious.
Çok lezzetli.
Yes.
Evet.
I'm sorry. Thank you.
Özür dilerim. Teşekkürler.
Conis.
Conis-san.
Conis, come and try some.
Conis-san, gel de bir tadına bak.
Young lady,
Genç hanım,
are you aware of those known as "pirates" in the Blue Sea?
onlara Mavi Deniz'de "korsan" deniyor, biliyor musun?
No.
Hayır.
They are criminals who travel on the ocean below.
Onlar, Mavi Deniz'de dolaşan suçlular.
Their ships all fly a black flag with a skull that varies from crew to crew.
Hepsi kuru kafalı bir siyah bayrak taşır ama her tayfanınki farklıdır.
Those Straw Hat fellows are probably pirates too.
O Hasır Şapkalar da muhtemelen öyle insanlar.
My word!
Aman tanrım!
Are you saying that they were criminals all along?
Başından beri suçlu olduklarını mı söylüyorsun?
Well...
Galiba...
More accurately, they do not live by the rules of the Blue Sea.
Suçlu yerine aykırı daha uygun bir kelime.
In any society, there are always those who don't fit in.
Her toplumda kurallara uymayı reddedenler vardır.
How is it any different from how you are now?
Sizin şu anki hâlinizden farkları ne?
Who can say for certain
Toplumun "doğru" yolda olduğunu,
that society is right and that those who don't fit in are wrong?
uyum sağlamayanların ise "yanlış" yolda olduğunu kim iddia edebilir ki?!
It's not always so black and white.
Her şeyin bir de gri tonu vardır.
To put it in extreme terms,
İşin özü şu:
a warhero from one era is considered a murderer in another.
Bir dönemin savaş kahramanı, başka bir dönemde katil olarak anılır.
I also have a pirate friend.
Benim de korsan bir arkadaşım var.
He came here when I was still god over twenty years ago.
Buraya yirmi küsur yıl önce, ben henüz tanrıyken gelmişti.
He was...
O...
quite the compassionate and pleasant fellow.
Koca yürekli, cana yakın biriydi.
It was a shame to say goodbye.
Veda etmek çok üzücüydü.
It may not seem like it at first glance, but Skypiea is ravaged by endless war...
Bunu bilmezsin ama Skypiea hep savaş içinde olan bir ülke.
where the sky people...
Biz gökyüzü insanları ve...
and the Shandian guerrillas battle continuously.
Shandialı gerillalar sürekli bir savaş hâlindeyiz.
Even now, the Shandians are still challenging Enel.
Shandialılar, şu an Enel'e meydan okumaya devam ediyorlar.
Your attempt to coexist with the Shandians when you were god
Siz tanrıyken Shandialılara ılımlı yaklaşımın,
offered hope that the centuries-long war would end peacefully.
insanlarda yüzyıllardır süren savaşın biteceği umudunu yeşertmişti.
Yes...
Evet...
I was very close to succeeding before Enel usurped my title of god.
Savaşı bitirmeye çok yakındım, ta ki Enel yerime geçene kadar.
I'm sorry.
Özür dilerim.
Everything worsened because of that.
Sonrasında her şey kötüye gitti.
Wh-What are you saying?! There's no need to apologize.
N-Ne diyorsunuz?! Özür dilemenize gerek yok.
There's a legend in Skypiea passed down from long ago:
Skypiea'da eskiden kalma bir mit vardır.
Once upon a time,
Çok uzun zaman önce,
on the day that Upper Yard, the sacred ground, was born,
kutsal Yukarı Bahçe'nin meydana geldiği o günde...
the island's beautiful song enveloped Skypiea.
adada çok güzel bir ses yankılanıp tüm ülkeye yayılmış.
That's when the battle between the Shandians and the sky people began...
Ve o vakit başlamış gökyüzü insanları ile Shandialılar arasındaki savaş...
as if that voice was a cue.
Sanki o ses bir işaretmiş gibi...
So, when we hear the "song of the island," this battle will end.
Bu yüzden gelecek sefer "adanın şarkısını" duyduğumuzda savaşın biteceğine inanıyorum.
The song of the island?
Adanın şarkısı mı?
That's right.
Evet.
The sacred ground will sing again...
Kutsal toprak bir kez daha şarkı söyleyecek.
someday, for sure.
Buna yürekten inanıyorum.
What's the matter?
Sorun nedir?
Please look after this place.
Lütfen buralara göz kulak olun.
I've got a job to do. Let's go, Pierre!
İşim çıktı. Hadi gidelim, Pierre!
Father, this pumpkin juice is delicious!
Baba, bu kabak suyu çok lezzetli!
Yes.
Evet.
I'm glad...
Beğendiğine...
that you can enjoy it.
sevindim.
Stop it!
Dur!
Please stop it!
Lütfen dur!
Don't harm the ship!
Gemiye zarar verme!
Anything but the ship!
Gemiye dokunma!
Dammit!
Lanet olsun!
Stop it already!
Dur artık!
I-I'm in charge of this ship!
B-Bu gemi bana emanet!
They asked me to look after it!
Benden gemiye göz kulak olmamı istediler!
Well...
Peki...
what should we do, Fuza?
ne yapalım o zaman, Fuza?
Fuza Nine-Meter Bird
Fuza Dokuz Metrelik Kuş
He says not to harm his friends.
"Arkadaşlarıma zarar verme" diyor.
He says not to damage the ship.
"Gemiye zarar verme" diyor.
He says he doesn't want to die.
"Ölmek istemiyorum" diyor.
What a dilemma.
İçinden çıkılmaz bir durum.
"Sky Rider" Shura Skypiea Priest
"Gökyüzü Binicisi" Shura Skypiea Rahibi
Such a damn selfish animal!
Bencil sefil yaratık!
He really irks me!
Canımı sıkıyor!
Gan Fall...
Gan Fall...
How can a weak thing like you cling to life so hopelessly?
Senin gibi güçsüz biri hayata nasıl bu kadar tutunabiliyor?
Stop it!
Dur!
That spear is burning everything!
O mızrak her şeyi yakıyor!
Dammit!
Kahretsin!
You bastard!
Seni şerefsiz!
Wha...?
N...?
You intend to go on living...
Hiçbir şey feda etmeden...
unprepared as you are to make a sacrifice?
yaşamaya devam etmeyi mi düşünüyorsun?
What is this guy?
Bu herif de ne böyle?
It's as if he can predict my moves.
Her hareketimi öngörebiliyor gibi.
For someone to live, another must die.
Birinin yaşaması için başkası ölmeli.
That is the rule of life.
Hayatın kuralı budur.
Did you know that this is a sacrificial altar?
Burası bir adak sunağı bilmiyor musun?
Y-Yeah!
E-Evet!
I heard something like that.
Öyle bir şey duymuştum.
It's true.
Doğru.
The rest of your group is desperately trying to get here.
Arkadaşların çaresizce buraya gelmeye çalışıyorlar.
On this island, there are four separate areas that we priests govern.
Bu adada biz rahiplerin kontrol ettiği...
Iron Balls Swamp
Demir Top İp Bataklık
String
dört farklı bölge var.
The rule is that when the targets set foot in one area,
Kurala göre birinin bölgesine giren olursa,
the other priests must leave them alone.
diğer rahipler onlara dokunmaz.
But this sacrificial altar doesn't belong to any of their zones.
Ama bu sunak kimsenin bölgesine dahil değil.
Sacrificial Altar
Adak Sunağı
In other words, it's a free area.
Yani, serbest bölgedir.
It's fair game for whoever gets here first.
Sunaktakini ilk gelen kapar.
Of course, we normally wait until after the ordeal ends in death.
Tabii normalde teste tabi tutulanların ölmesini bekleriz.
What?!
Ne?!
Then, Luffy, Sanji, and Usopp are...?!
O zaman, Luffyler...
Calm down.
Sakin ol.
My presence here doesn't mean your friends are dead...
Benim burada olmam onların öldüğü anlamına gelmiyor...
unfortunately.
maalesef.
I came here for a completely different reason.
Ben buraya başka bir sebeple geldim.
What?!
Ne?!
A different reason...?
Ne sebebi...?
So then, does that mean we can get out of here
O hâlde Luffy ve diğerleri buraya ulaşabilirlerse,
if Luffy's group comes to rescue us?!
buradan gidebilir miyiz?!
Yeah, that's right...
Evet, bu doğru...
If you can escape the free area, that is.
Serbest bölgeden çıkabilirseniz tabii.
What?
Ne?
Just hold that thought.
Onu boş ver şimdi.
The reason I came here is because,
Buraya geldim çünkü...
although those are the normal rules for reckoning,
standart kurallar böyle ama...
when there's an exceptional situation, they change a little.
olağanüstü bir durum olduğunda kurallar biraz değişir.
Exceptional...
Olağanüstü...
That's right.
Evet.
Case in point:
Mesela:
Three sacrifices make an unauthorized escape to the forest using vines.
Kurbanlardan üçü, sarmaşığı kullanarak ormana izinsiz girerlerse...
Huh... Does that happen?
Haa... Demek sorun bu...?
There's a god on this island, right?
Bu adada bir tanrı var, değil mi?
I'm gonna go meet him.
Gidip tanışacağım.
This is all his fault!
Bunlar hep onun suçu!
Someone has to die to atone for the others' sin of escaping.
Biri kaçanların işlediği günaha karşılık, ölmek zorunda.
Sacrifice is the truth of this world.
Bu dünya fedakârlık üzerine kuruludur.
This way, if they return,
Böylece geri dönerlerse...
they will realize their individual faults
arkadaşlarının cesedeni görüp...
when they see their friend dead.
yaptıkları hatanın farkına varacaklar.
Offer your life to God!
Hayatını Tanrı'ya feda et!
No way!
Olmaz!
Perish.
Geber!
Sorry to have kept you waiting!
Beklettiğim için üzgünüm!
Sky Knight!
Gökyüzü Şövalyesi!
It seems we are entertaining a surprise guest!
Görünüşe göre sürpriz bir konuğumuz var!
Gan Fall!
Gan Fall!
Sky Knight!
Gökyüzü Şövalyesi!
He is quite a skilled and worthy opponent.
O oldukça yetenekli ve güçlü bir rakip.
Let's get a bit rougher with him, Pierre.
Vitesi biraz arttıralım, Pierre.
What’s that decrepit fossil doing here?!
Bu yıkık bunak burada ne arıyor?!
Shall we play with him a little, Fuza?!
Onunla biraz eğlensek mi, Fuza?!
Do your worst!
Elinden geleni ardına koyma!
We don't need two gods on this island!
Bu adada iki tanrıya ihtiyacımız yok!
Go!
Hadi!
Sky Knight!
Gökyüzü Şövalyesi!
We need to give him one more push, Pierre.
Aynısını bir kez daha yapmalıyız, Pierre.
Let's go!
Hadi gidelim!
You son of a bitch!
Şerefsiz!
You probably came here knowing this, but...
Buraya bunu bilerek geldin ama...
you're a wanted criminal!
sen aranan bir suçlusun!
Yes, you'll see how I deal with aggravating fools like yourself!
Senin gibi can sıkıcı ahmaklara ne yaptığımı göreceksin!
Ordeal of String!
İp Testi!
You're still alive?
Hâlâ hayatta mısın?
Impressive indeed!
Gerçekten etkileyici!
Well, then, as a reward, I'll give you my prized finishing blow!
Madem öyle, ödül olarak sana en özel bitirici vuruşumu hediye edeceğim!
Surprise Balls!
Ejder Topu!
Shandian Settlement of Guerrillas Village Hidden in the Clouds
Shandialı Gerillaların Yerleşkesi Saklı Bulut Köyü
Aisa!
Aisa!
Where have you been?
Neredeydin?
Kamakiri!
Kamakiri!
Upper Yard again?
Yukarı Bahçe'ye mi gittin yine?
You've got vearth in your bag, don't you?
Çantanda vearth var, değil mi?
Don't go there too often...
Oraya sık sık gitme...
or you'll lose your life.
yoksa ölürsün.
Don't tell me what to do!
Bana emir verme!
You haven't even beaten Enel yet!
Daha Enel'i yenemedin!
Damn brat.
Kahrolası velet!
An opening?
Şans mı?
That's right.
Evet.
For some reason, Gan Fall has entered Upper Yard.
Bir sebeple Gan Fall, Yukarı Bahçe'ye girdi.
That old geezer thinks he can settle everything in Skypiea peacefully.
O yaşlı bunak, hâlâ Skypiea'daki her şeyi barışçıl yollarla çözebileceğine inanıyor.
He's got it all wrong.
Yanılıyor.
Victory or defeat.
Zafer veya yenilgi.
Those are the only two outcomes in a battle.
Savaşın sadece iki sonucu vardır.
Warrior of Shandora Wyper A Shandian
Shandora Savaşçısı Wyper Shandialı
The great warrior Kalgara said,
Şanlı Savaşçı Kalgara'nın dediği gibi,
"Shine the Light of Shandora."
"Shandora'nın Işığını Yakın."
We'll follow those words.
Yapacağımız da bu.
It doesn't matter who we have to fight—
Kimle savaşmamız gerekirse gereksin—
the former god Gan Fall or Enel.
Eski tanrı Gan Fall veya Enel.
So long as they reign as god,
Tanrı olarak hüküm sürdükleri sürece,
they're all the same to us no matter what form they take.
bizim için bir farkları yok.
They all have to be eliminated!
Hepsinin yok edilmesi gerekiyor!
Wyper.
Wyper.
Someone on Angel Island rebelled against Enel.
Melek Adası'nda biri Enel'e isyan etmiş.
I heard it was a young woman.
Genç bir kadınmış.
This is the first rebel in the six years since Enel began his reign.
Enel'in altı yıllık hükmündeki ilk isyan bu.
So what?
Yani?
Since Gan Fall saved her from reckoning,
Gan Fall onu ilahi adaletten kurtardığına göre,
Enel now has a reason to judge even the former god.
artık Enel'in eski tanrıyı da cezalandırma hakkı var.
Gan Fall has never harmed any of us,
Gan Fall hiçbirimize zarar vermedi,
whether as the Sky Knight or as the former god...
ne Gökyüzü Şövalyesi olarak ne de tanrıyken...
nor has he tried to directly confront Enel.
ama Enel'in karşısına da çıkmadı.
But that same man has finally entered Upper Yard.
Ama bu adam sonunda Yukarı Bahçe'ye girdi.
If he and a priest happen to kill each other, so much the better.
Eğer rahiplerden biriyle birbirlerini öldürürlerse çok iyi olur.
Or do you mean to say that Gan Fall is no longer our enemy?
Yoksa Gan Fall artık düşmanımız değil mi demek istiyorsun?
When people have a common enemy,
Ortak düşmanımızın olması...
that they are now allies is a delusion!
bizi dost yapmaz!
If you have doubts, then stay out of the fight, Raki!
Bununla bir sorunun varsa savaştan uzak dur, Raki!
You'll only get in our way!
Sadece bize engel olacaksın!
Aisa!
Aisa!
What?! It's not like I went to Upper Yard or anything!
Ne?! Yukarı Bahçe'ye falan gitmedim ben!
Don't go into the tent right now.
Çadıra girme şu an.
Wyper– That is, the descendant of the great warrior, Kalgara, is angry.
Wyper pardon, Şanlı Savaşçı Kalgara'nın varisi, çok sinirli.
Yeah, that's scary.
Evet, çok korkunç.
He's scarier than God...
Tanrı'dan bile korkunç..
Help...
Yardım mı...
them?
edelim?
Us?
Biz mi?
Yes, that's right.
Evet, edelim.
Let's try to create a way for them to escape somehow.
Onların kaçması için bir yol bulalım.
I can't even tell what they're doing...
Ne yaptıklarını bile bilmiyorum...
Amazing!
Harika!
It seems my negotiations with your group are over!
Anlaşılan sizlerle müzakere etmek artık mümkün değil!
You're as soft as ever!
Her zamanki gibi çok yumuşaksın!
What... is this fight?
Bu dövüş de ne böyle?
Divine Reckoning...
İlahi Adalet...
What that girl did was foolish.
O kızın yaptığı ahmakçaydı.
We should never...
Tanrı Enel'i...
anger God Enel.
asla kızdırmamalıyız.
Please come back...
Lütfen geri dönün...
God!
Tanrı'm!
I've got you now.
İşin bitti.
Is something wrong, Gan Fall?!
Bir sorun mu var, Gan Fall?!
What did you do?!
Ne yaptın sen?!
Why?! Why can't we move?!
Neden?! Neden hareket edemiyoruz?!
A dying man...
Ölecek olan birinin...
needs no answer.
cevaba ihtiyacı yok.
The mysterious Ordeal of String!
Esrarengiz İp Testi!
Even you may enter Upper Yard,
Yukarı Bahçe'ye girersen,
but you will be subject to our trials all the same.
dört rahip tarafından da test edilirsin!
Don't think that we can be beaten so easily!
O kadar kolay yenileceğimizi sanma!
God Enel...
Tanrı Enel...
is a glorious and inaccessible being.
yüce, ulaşılmaz bir varlıktır.
That's right.
Evet.
The sacred ground will sing again...
Kutsal toprak bir kez daha şarkı söyleyecek.
someday, for sure.
Buna yürekten inanıyorum.
Sky...
Gökyüzü...
Sky Knight!
Gökyüzü Şövalyesi!